# 大家好 這兩天都沒檢雞蛋
Hi everyone! I've not been picking eggs these two days.
# 差不多有四五天哦 不止兩天了
I think it's almost four or five days, not just two.
# 看下有沒有雞蛋 就在這裡面
Let me see if there are any eggs. They're right here inside.
# 你看這個貓
Look at this cat!
# 它在幹嘛
What is it doing?
# 太壞了
Naughty!
# 誒呀 有雞蛋哦 好多哦
Ayo! I see eggs! A lot of eggs!
# 這兩個
Two here
# 這個雞是我媽 我媽自己餵的
These hens are my mom's.They're kept by my mom.
# 沒有
Nothing
# 這裡 這裡有四個
Here, here are four.
# 啊 這麼大
Ah! They're so big!
# 這些雞沒有甚麼雞窩的
These hens don't have a roost whatsoever.
# 它就在一個坑裡面
They simply find a pit,
# 它就下蛋啦
and lay the eggs there.
# 你看 這個桶裡面都下了蛋
Look! They lay eggs even in this basket.
# 你看 這裡有三個
Look! Here are three.
# 桶裡面也有蛋
They lay eggs even in a basket.
# 哇 這裡面 咦
Wa! Here inside, yi?
# 那是小皃蛋嗎 還是公雞蛋
Is it an egg of a little bird, or is it from a cock?
# 你看這個雞蛋 那麼小的
Look at this egg! It's so small.
# 像我的手指頭那麼大一點
It's just a bit larger than my fingertip.
# 甚麼蛋啊這個
What kind of egg is it?
# 是不是雞蛋
Is it really a chicken egg?
# 你看這個
Look at these!
# 真的好小啊 這樣的
These are really small, see?
# 這 這樣的 (註︰這些碎碎念不能得直譯了，變成英文的碎碎念算了)
Really, really small
# 這肯定兩個母雞下的 下是一個母雞下的
They must be from two different hens. They can't be from the same hen.
# 這裡有一個
Here's one.
# 誒呦 這裡又那麼多個
Eyo! There are so many too.
# 你看 這個總共十九個雞蛋
Look! Here I have nineteen eggs in total.
# 有些白的 有些黃的
Some are white, some are brown.
# 這個黑母雞下的雞該
These should be from a black hen, I think.
# 這種就是 花母雞下的
And these are from the black-and-brown hens.
# 這個
This one,
# 是下是公雞下的 這個蛋 那麼小
is it from a cock? It's so small.
# 肯定是第 第一次下蛋
It must be its first, first time laying eggs.
# 下小一蛋
So the eggs are smaller.
# 這兩個也好小 這個兩個
These two are really small, these two,
# 像個小鳥蛋一樣
just like eggs of little birds.
# 沒事
Never mind
# 不影響 不影響肉質
The texture, the texture is just as good.
# 一樣可以吃的 那麼小的
They're also edible, despite the small size.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻到這裡啦
The video ends here.